A Guide to the Clerk's Correspondence and other Records, 1918-2006
Virginia State Law Library, Supreme Court of Virginia Archives
- Clerk's general correspondence, 1929-1981, 3.0 boxes (Box 5-7 to 8-3 and 13-1 to 13-8)
  - Correspondence, M.B. Watts and Wirt Johnson Turner Carrington, 1923-1926, 3 folders (Box-folder 8-1 to 8-3)
    Maury B. Watts, Clerk of the Supreme Court of Virginia from 1933 to 1954, was associated with Appeals Press, in Richmond, which published Carrington's book, A History of Halifax County, in 1924. The correspondence pertains to marketing and sales of the book.
- Subject files: investitures, 1965-2005, 25 folders (Box 8-4 to 9-7)
  This series contains subject files documenting swearing-in ceremonies and investitures. It contains invitations, programs, oaths of office, transcripts of ceremonies, speeches and remarks, and sometimes seating charts and ceremony planning notes.
  - Justice George Steven Agee, 2003 Mar. 5 (Box-folder 8-4)
  - David Bernard Beach, Clerk, 1984 Oct. 31 (Box-folder 8-5)
  - Justice Harry Lee Carrico, 1962 Feb. 2; 1981, 1991 (Box-folder 8-6 to 8-7)
  - Justice George Moffett Cochran, 1974 Oct. 1 (Box-folder 8-8)
  - Justice Asbury Christian Compton, 1974 Oct. 1 (Box-folder 8-9)
  - Justice Thomas Christian Gordon, Jr., 1965 Feb. 17 (Box-folder 8-10)
  - Karl Robert Hade, Executive Secretary, 2005 Sep. 12 (Box-folder 8-11)
  - Justice Alexander Marrs Harman, 1969 Oct. 1 (Box-folder 8-12)
  - Patricia Leas Harrington, Clerk, 2003 Aug. 27 (Box-folder 8-13)
  - Justice Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr., 2003 Aug. 27 (Box-folder 8-14)
  - Justice Leroy Rountree Hassell, Sr., 1989 Dec. 28l 2003 Feb. 11 (Box-folder 8-15 to 8-16)
  - Chief Justice Lawrence Warren I'Anson, 1974 Oct. 1 (Box-folder 8-17)
  - Justice Barbara Milano Keenan, 1991 Jul. 2 (Box-folder 8-18)
  - Justice Cynthia Dinah Fannon Kinser, 1997 Jun. 27 (Box-folder 8-19)
  - Justice Lawrence Larkins Koontz, Jr., 1995 Aug. 16 (Box-folder 8-20)
  - Justice Elizabeth Bermingham Lacy, 1989 Jan. 4 (Box-folder 8-21)
  - Justice Donald Wayne Lemons, 2000 Apr. 4 (Box-folder 9-1)
  - Justice Richard Harding Poff, 1972 Aug. 30 (Box-folder 9-2)
  - Justice Charles Stevens Russell, 1982 Mar. 5 (Box-folder 9-3)
  - Justice Harold Fleming Snead, 1969 (Box-folder 9-4)
  - Justice Roscoe Bolar Stephenson, Jr., 1981 Mar. 2 (Box-folder 9-5)
  - Justice John Charles Thomas, 1983 Apr. 25 (Box-folder 9-6)
  - Justice William Carrington Thompson, 1980 Feb. 1 (Box-folder 9-7)
- Subject files: portrait presentations and memorials, 1925-2005 (Box-folder 9-8 to 11-8)
  This series contains materials documenting portrait presentations and memorial ceremonies honoring justices and other officers of the Supreme Court of Virginia. The files contain invitations, programs, transcripts of ceremonies, including remarks; printed memorials, resolutions of appreciation (legislative and judicial), and in some cases planning notes, seating charts, and newspaper clippings.
  - David Beach, Clerk, 2003 Jun. 6 (Box-folder 9-8)
  - Justice George Landon Browning, 1940; 1948 Jan. 9 (Box-folder 9-9)
  - Justice Archibald Chapman Buchanan, 1965-1980 (Box-folder 9-10)
  - Justice John Alexander Buchanan, 1921, circa (Box-folder 9-11)
  - Justice Preston White Campbell, 1954, 1959 (Box-folder 9-12)
  - Chief Justice Harry Lee Carrico, 1990; 2001 (Box-folder 9-13)
  - Justice Joseph William Chinn, 1941 (Box-folder 9-14)
  - Justice George Moffett Cochran, 1989 Apr. 20 (Box-folder 9-15)
  - Justice Asbury Christian Compton, 2000, circa (Box-folder 9-16)
  - Chief Justice John William Eggleston, 1965; 1969 1976 Oct. 7 (Box-folder 9-17)
  - Thomas Christian Gordon, Jr., 2003-2004 (Box-folder 9-18)
  - Justice Herbert Bailey Gregory, 1952 Apr. 21 (Box-folder 9-19)
  - Justice Alexander Marrs Harman, Jr., 1987 (Box-folder 10-1)
  - Justice Albertis Sydney Harrison, Jr., 1984 Oct. 12 (Box-folder 10-2)
  - Chief Justice Henry Winston Holt, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 10-3)
  - Chief Justice Edward Wren Hudgins, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 10-4 to 10-5)
  - Justice Lawrence Warren I'Anson, 1983 Jun. 15 (Box-folder 10-6)
  - Judge James Keith, Court President, 1925 Oct. 30 (Box-folder 10-7)
  - Allen L. Lucy, Clerk, 1984 (Box-folder 10-8)
  - Judge James Mercer, 1978 Apr. 20 (Box-folder 10-9)
  - Justice Willis Dance Miller, 1961 Apr. 17 (Box-folder 10-10)
  - Justice Richard Harding Poff, 2005 Nov. 1 (Box-folder 10-11)
  - Justice Lemuel Franklin Smith, 1957 Mar. 4 (Box-folder 11-1)
  - Chief Justice Harold Fleming Snead, 1982 Jun 4 (Box-folder 11-2)
  - Justice Claude Vernon Spratley, 1977 Jun. 9 (Box-folder 11-3 to 11-4)
  - Justice Abram Penn Staples, 1952 Apr. 21 (Box-folder 11-5)
  - Justice W. Carrington Thompson, 2005 Nov. 1 (Box-folder 11-6)
  - Howard G. Turner, Clerk, 1977; 1992 (Box-folder 11-7)
  - Maury B. Watts, Clerk, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 11-8)
  - Justice Henry H. Whiting, 2005 Nov. 1 (Box-folder 11-9)
  - Justice Kennon Caithness Whittle, 1968 Oct. 14 (Box-folder 11-10)
- Subject files: court anniversaries and building dedications, 1941-1943; 1979-2006, 7 folders (Box 11-11 to 12-1)
  This series contains programs, speeches, transcripts, and correspondence documenting celebrations of court anniversaries and building dedications.
  - Dedication of Building, Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 1941 Jan. 6, 1 folder (Box-folder 11-10)
    Program and addresses.
  - 200th anniversary, establishment of the Supreme Court of Virginia, 1979 Aug. 30, 1 folder (Box-folder 11-11)
    Programs and speeches.
  - 200th anniversary, first session of the Virginia Supreme Court, 1980, 1 item (Box-folder 11-12)
    Henrico County Circuit Court order commemorating the anniversary.
  - Dedication of the Supreme Court of Virginia Building, 1981 Dec. 4, 1 item (2 copies) (Box-folder 11-13)
    Program.
  - 200th anniversary of the establishment of the federal judiciary, 1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 11-14)
    Correspondence and transcript of ceremony.
  - 225th anniversary, establishment of the Virginia Supreme Court, 2004 Dec. 9, 1 folder (Box-folder 11-15)
    Programs, draft speeches, transcript, invitation, and certificate of recognition.
  - 230th anniversary, enactment of Virginia's first Constitution, 2006 Nov. 2, 1 folder (Box-folder 12-1)
    Invitation and program.
- Subject files: court admission ceremonies, 1977-1978; 1980-1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 12-2)
  This series contains programs from admission ceremonies, held at the Hotel John Marshall in Richmond, for attorneys at law qualifying to practice in the Supreme Court of Virginia and all courts in the Commonwealth of Virginia.
- Justices' speeches, 1931-1975, 1 folder (Box 12-3)
  Speeches honoring individuals or explaining the functions of the Court.
  - Presentation of Chief Justice Hughes at the dinner tendered him by the Virginia State Bar Association and the Bar Association of the City of Richmond, at the Commonwealth Club, Richmond, 1931 Sep. 29
  - Justice George L. Browning, Address to Virginia State Bar Association meeting in Roanoke, 1943 Aug.
  - Judge Paul Carrington, an Address Delivered by Justice John W. Eggleston of the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia at the Dedication of a Memorial to Him at Mulberry Hill in Charlotte County, 1954 Jun. 26.
  - An Address Delivered at the Dedication of a Bust to George Wythe at William and Mary College, Williamsburg, Virginia, by Justice C. Vernon Spratley, Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, 1954 Sep. 29.
  - "How the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia Functions," an address by the Honorable Lawrence W. I'Anson, Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, before the Virginia State Bar Association, 1960 Aug. 5.
  - "The Supreme Court of Appeals," an address by Justice Harry Carrico to the Virginia Clerks Association, 1961 Aug. 3
  - Admissions Day Ceremony Remarks by Chief Justice Eggleston, Richmond, Va., 1966 Jun. 9
  - Address by Justice Carrico to the Richmond Association of Attorneys' Wives, 1975 Dec. 7
  - Introduction for Delegate Watkins Abbott, Fourth Congressional District, 1953, circa.
  - Remarks, "Welcome to the Bar," undated
- Court publications, 1983, 9 pamphlets. (Box 12-4)
  Informational pamphlets published by the Supreme Court of Virginia: Virginia Courts in Brief, and the Supreme Court of Virginia.
- Clippings, 1972; undated, 1 folder (Box 12-5)
  Clippings about the closing of the Supreme Court of Appeals in Staunton in 1972; and photographs of the Judicial Conference, undated, published in the Virginia Bar News.
- Miscellaneous records, 1936-2005., 6 folders (Box 12-6 to 12-9)
  This series contains court orders, architectural plans, and memos.
  - Blueprints, alterations to Supreme Court Building, 1958, 1967, 1 folder (Box-folder 12-6)
  - Program, Conference of Chief Justices Visit Virginia, 1950 Sep., 2 items (Box-folder 12-7)
  - Various court orders, 1942-2005, 10 items (Box-folder 12-8)
  - Various records, 1936-2001, 14 items (Box-folder 12-9)
    Various court documents and other records filed with records from the Clerk's office. Includes copies, undated, of pages of the Supreme Court of Appeals order book, 1785 and 1810; motions, jury instructions, a biographical sketch of John Blair, originally published in the Virginia Bar Association annual report, 1927; a resolution thanking Justice Hudgins for his assistance furnishing the new court building, 1940; jury instructions, and a memo from Justice Lacy to the other justices about multi-jurisdictional practice, 2001.